{
    "id": "3a4ff8e3e3334eb181a12ce76784d879",
    "title": "Tenses quiz",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "This time tomorrow, I ............................... on the beach.",
            "description": "To say that an activity will be in progress at a particular time in the future, we use the future continuous tense.",
            "answers": [
                "am lying",
                "will lie",
                "will be lying"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She said that she ....................... help me.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "shall",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Phone me when you ............................ time.",
            "description": "In many subordinate clauses we use the present tenses to refer to the future. ",
            "answers": [
                "have",
                "would have",
                "will have"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I will follow you wherever you ...........................",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the future tense, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future. ",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "goes",
                "will go"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You ........................... an accident if you go on driving like that.",
            "description": "In conditional sentences, when the verb in the if-clause is in the simple present tense, we use will + infinitive in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "are having",
                "will have",
                "would have"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "When you phoned, I ................................. in the garage.",
            "description": "We use the past continuous to talk about a past event that was going on a particular time in the past. ",
            "answers": [
                "worked",
                "am working",
                "was working"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I .............................. all my childhood in South India.",
            "description": "The simple past is the normal tense for talking about the past. We use it when we don't have a special reason to use another tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "was spending",
                "spend",
                "spent"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The phone ......................... while I was having a bath.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to refer to shorter actions that happen in the middle of a longer action.",
            "answers": [
                "rings",
                "rang",
                "was ringing"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I tried a little of the soup to see how it ..........................",
            "description": "Some verbs are not normally used in the continuous form. Taste is one of them.",
            "answers": [
                "tastes",
                "is tasting",
                "tasted"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "When we were children we ............................. our own toys.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about habitual past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "were making",
                "made",
                "had made"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I can't dance because I ........................... my leg.",
            "description": "The present tense is used to say that a finished action is connected with the present in some way.",
            "answers": [
                "have broken",
                "broke",
                "had broken"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I .......................... the bell six times but no one opened the door.",
            "description": "We use the simple past to talk about repeated past actions.",
            "answers": [
                "was ringing",
                "have rung",
                "rang"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}